There are quite a few choices when it comes to choosing a JavaScript chart library.
在选择 JavaScript 图表库时 有很多选项
I chose Plotly for this lesson because it has
对于本课程 我选择了 Plotly
both a JavaScript library and also a Python version.
因为它既有 JavaScript 库 也有 Python 版本
Since the back end of this web app will be in Python,
由于此 Web 应用的后端将使用 Python
you can actually use the Plotly Python library in your back end.
你实际上可以在后端使用 Plotly Python 库
Plotly, just so you know,
Plotly 如你所知
is actually a company,
实际上是一家公司
but their charting libraries are open-source.
但他们的图表库是开源的
Since you haven't made the back end yet,
既然你还没有做到后端
for this part of the lesson,
对于本课程的这一部分
I'm going to show you the JavaScript version of the Plotly library.
我将展示 Plotly 库的 JavaScript 版本
The syntax and ideas behind the Python and JavaScript version are quite similar.
Python 和 JavaScript 版本语法和背后的思想都非常相似
So, when you end up using the Python Plotly library later in the lesson,
因此 当你最后在课程中使用 Python Plotly 库时
it won't be too different.
不会有太大不同
To make a plot,
要绘制一个图表
all you need to do is create a div element with a specific ID.
你需要做的就是创建一个具有特定 id 的 div 元素
So, you can see here,
这里你可以看到
I have a basic HTML document.
我有一个基础的 HTML 文档
All I've done is linked to the JavaScript source file of the Plotly library.
现在完成的就是链接到 Plotly 库的 JavaScript 源文件
Then, I've created a div down here with ID plot1.
然后 我在这里用 id plot1 创建了一个 div
Also, links to a script called plot1.js where
另外 链接到一个名为 plot1.js 的脚本
I'm going to write the JavaScript code to make the plot appear.
编写 JavaScript 代码将图表绘制出来
I'm going to put the plotly code into this file plot1.js.
我会将 plotly 代码放到这个 plot1.js 文件中
So, essentially, all you need to do is have
基本上 你需要做的就是使用一些数据
some data and then tell plotly what kind of plot you want to make.
然后告诉 plotly 你想要绘制什么样的图表
So, in this case,
在当前示例中
I'm going to put some data into a couple of JavaScript lists.
我将一些数据放入两个 JavaScript 列表中
So, this is just regular JavaScript code.
这只是常规的 JavaScript 代码
I'm creating some data that has a year as
我创建的数据中有一个变量是 year
one variable and then arable_land is another variable.
arable_land 是另一个变量
This is real data that I've taken from the World Bank website.
这是我从世界银行网站上获取的真实数据
Okay. Now, comes the plotly code.
好的 现在开始编写 plotly 代码
So, I'm going to make a variable that I'm going to call
我要创建一个变量 叫做 trace1
a trace and a trace is essentially
trace (痕迹)  实际上也是一种可视化
a visualization or you can think of it as a part of
或者你可以将其视为可视化的一部分
a visualization like a single line or a set of points.
就像一条折线 或者一组散点
You'll see what I mean in a second.
你马上就能明白我是什么意思
So, I'm going to specify the X variable as year,
将 x 变量指定为 year
the Y variable as arable_land,
y 变量指定为 arable_land
and then I'm going to say, mode: 'lines' because I want to make a line chart,
然后选择 mode:'lines' 因为我想绘制折线图
and then I'm going to specify the type as a scatter plot.
然后指定类型为散点图
So, this is actually essentially a dictionary that I'm making in
我现在写的实际是一个 JavaScript 字典
JavaScript where I'm specifying all the parts of this visualization.
设置可视化的各个部分
So, I'm going to make another list where I'm going to keep this trace and call it data.
我将创建另一个列表 data 在其中保存 trace1
Then, the last part, I just say, Plotly.newPlot.
最后 只需要写出 Plotly.newPlot()
So, I'm calling the Plotly library, newPlot method,
也就是调用 Plotly 库 newPlot 方法
and then I say plot1 because that was the ID we used in the HTML,
然后传入 plot1 因为那是我们在 HTML 中使用的 id
insert the data, and it should work.
传入 data 应该就可以完成了
There we go. This is the plot I made.
好啦 这就是我做的图表
So, this plot isn't perfect.
这个图表并不完美
It's missing a title, for example,
比如 缺少标题
and it's missing x and y-axis labels, so let's add that.
缺少 x 轴和 y 轴的标签 所以我们来添加一下
I'm going to add another variable called layout and this is
我要添加另一个名为 layout 的变量
going to be another dictionary with the information I want to put in like the title.
这个变量也是一个字典 其中包含我想要输入的信息 比如标题
I'm going to put in this br,
在其中加一个 br 标签
which is actually HTML for a break in the line,
这实际上是 HTML 中的换行
so that the title will render on two different lines.
这样标题就会显示为两行
Now, I'm going to specify some things about the x-axis.
现在 我将指定一些关于 x 轴的设置
This is going to be within a dictionary because there are various options.
这些设置在一个字典中 因为有多种选项
So, I'm going to say, title: 'year'.
我要设置 title: 'year'
I'm going to say, actually,
然后设置 tick
that I want the tick to start at 1990 and I want the delta between the ticks 325.
我希望 tick 在 1990 年开始 间距为 25
Now, I'm going to specify some things about
现在指定 y 轴设置
the y-axis like the title and then we're going to close this off.
比如标题 然后关闭括号
Now, we're going to add layout as the third input to the newPlot method.
现在 添加 layout 作为 newPlot 方法的第三个输入值
Okay. So, we made sure that the x-axis started at
好的 所以我们确保 x 轴开始于 1990 年
1990 and that there are only two points,
只有两个点
1990 and then a delta of 25 to 2015.
1990 年 然后是 25 年的间隔到 2015 年
We added the year as the x-axis label,
我们将 year 添加为 x 轴标签
and then we added the y-axis label, and a title.
还添加了 y 轴标签和图表标题
So, you can see how using Plotly,
所以 你看到如何使用 Plotly 了
you can build out a chart little by little with more and more features.
你可以逐步构建图表 添加越来越多的功能
So, let's make this visualization a little bit more complex.
让这个可视化变得更复杂一点
I have Brazil on here.
我在这里有巴西的数据
I want to add Germany,
我想增加德国的数据
so that Brazil and Germany appear at the same time.
这样巴西和德国同时出现在图表中
So, I'm going to change this variable and call it arable_land1.
修改此变量 将其命名为 arable_land1
Then, I'm going to make a country1 variable and call it Brazil.
然后创建一个 country1 变量并将其赋值为 'Brazil'
Okay. Now, I want arable_land1 as y-axis.
好的 现在我希望 arable_land1 作为 y 轴
I'm going to add this name here and say,
在这里添加 name 变量 对应值是 country1
country1, and that's going to be use for the legend, okay?
这会被用于图例中的名称
Now, I am going to add some information about Germany.
现在 添加一些关于德国的信息
Now, I need to create another trace,
我需要创建另一个 trace
trace2, to make a line for Germany.
trace2 为德国绘制一条折线
We're going to use the same year variable,
使用相同的 year 变量
arable_land2, specify the mode, specify the type.
arable_land2 指定模式 指定类型
Now, we're going to add trace2 to the data list and there we go.
现在 我们把 trace2 添加到 data 列表中 然后就好了
Just to give you some other ideas,
提供一些其他的思路
you can change the mode, for example,
比如 你可以修改模式
and change it from lines to markers,
将其从 lines 修改为 markers
and that just gives you points instead of a line or you could even say,
这会给你显示点 而不是折线 或者你甚至可以设置为
'lines+markers', and have both of them.
'lines+markers' 这样就都可以显示出来了
Okay. Now, let's add another plot.
好的 现在我们添加另一个图表
So, all I have to do here is add another div,
我要做的就是添加另一个 div
call it something else.
命名为其他名称
We're going to call it plot2.
我们用 plot2
Just for organization purposes,
只是为了更便于管理
I'm going to put it into a different file.
我把它放到另一个文件中
So, let's create this new file called plot2.
所以 创建一个名为 plot2 的新文件
So, in plot2, I'm going to make a bar chart to make something different.
在 plot2 中 我将绘制一个条形图 做些不一样的操作
I'm just going to put the data in directly instead of using the extra variables.
直接将数据放入 data 而不再使用额外的变量
Again, the data is just a list,
同样 data 是一个列表
a list of all the data points in order,
按顺序列出所有数据点
so that the X and Y match.
这样 x 和 y 匹配
I'm going to say, type is a bar chart because I want to do something different.
类型是条形图 因为我想做一些不同的操作
Let's close this, create a layout.
让我们关闭括号 创建一个布局 layout
I'm going to say, title: 'Hectares Arable Land Per Person 2015',
设置为 title: 'Hectares Arable Land Per Person 2015'
x-axis, let's give it a title,
x 轴 设置一个标题
y-axis, 'hectares per person' as a title.
y 轴 标题设置为 'hectares per person'
Then, we call the Plotly.newPlot method,
然后 调用 Plotly.newPlot 方法
make sure to specify the right name of the ID, put in the data,
确保指定正确的 id 名称 传入 data
put in the layout, and we've got our second chart down here.
传入 layout 我们在下面得到了第二张图表
So, it's up to you to decide what kind of chart is best for your data,
自己决定哪种图表最适用于你的数据
and you'll want to go to the Plotly website,
你可以去 Plotly 网站
and see all of their examples,
看到他们的所有示例
so that you can make the kind of chart you're trying to make.
这样你就可以绘制出你想要的图表
They have a lot of examples on their website.
他们网站上有很多例子
Again, you can take the code,
同样地 你可以直接将代码拿来使用
you can copy their example code,
复制他们的示例代码
and then you can fill it in with your own data,
然后替换为自己的数据
and change it any way you'd like.
按自己的喜好修改设置
Okay. The last thing I want to show you is putting together what you've made with
好了 我要展示的最后一件事 就是整合自己的工作
the Bootstrap library and putting in these Plotly plots.
将这些 Plotly 图表放入用 Bootstrap 库构建的网页中
So, here, I have the front end that you've been working
这里就是你之前使用 Bootstrap 构建的前端
with Bootstrap and I've put in a couple of extra things here.
我添加了一些额外的东西
So, way at the bottom,
在底部
I added some extra scripts tags.
我添加了一些额外的 scripts 标签
One links to the Plotly JavaScript library and
一个链接到 Plotly JavaScript 库
then two other ones are linking to the Plotly code that I was just writing before.
另外两个链接到我之前写的 Plotly 代码
So, they're linking to plot1.js and plot2.js.
也就是链接到 plot1.js 和 plot2.js
So, the only thing left is to put the divs with
现在唯一还要完成的就是
the correct IDs in the spot where I want to put the visualizations.
把拥有正确 id 的 div 放入预期的位置
Scrolling back up here,
滚动到上面
I have this row and these two columns.
这一行和这两列
So, that is where I want my plots to show up.
这就是我希望图表展示的地方
So, I'm going to make a new div,
我要写一个新的 div
and I'm going to say, id="plot1",
然后设置 id="plot1"
and then close the div.
然后关闭 div
I'm going to make another div,
写另一个 div
and say, id="plot2", and close the div.
设置 id="plot2" 然后关闭 div
Let's see what we've got.
让我们看看效果
Okay. So now, we've combined the CSS Bootstrap front end with
好的 我们已经将 CSS Bootstrap 前端与
the JavaScript visualizations using Plotly.
使用 Plotly 绘制的 JavaScript 可视化结合到一起了
The one part that's still missing in terms of
在前端方面仍然缺少一个部分
the front end is actually using data from say,
实际上数据的来源应该是
a CSV file or downloading data from the Internet,
CSV 文件或从互联网下载
but we'll get to that a little bit later in the lesson.
但是我们会在稍后的课程介绍
So, this is it essentially for the front end.
所以 这基本上就是前端的内容了
There's one exercise left to do and then you're going to start working on the back end.
还有一个练习要做 然后就进入后端的工作